respondus.com 2016-11-23

# Respondus.com Privacy Statement

Respondus, Inc. has created this statement to explain our commitment to your privacy. We seek to protect your private information so that you have an enjoyable experience on our web site. We will not sell, rent, trade, or disclose your personally identifiable information to anyone except as explained in this policy. 

Please return to this page from time to time, as we will be updating this statement to accommodate additional products and services. We welcome and encourage questions, comments, and suggestions. Please contact us at privacy@respondus.com. 

## **Personally Identifiable Information**

## Definition of Personally Identifiable Information

"Personally identifiable information" is your name, company, address, e-mail address, phone number(s) and credit card information. 

## Where We Collect Personally Identifiable Information

Respondus.com collects personally identifiable information when you (1) register a product, (2) make a purchase, (3) sign up for a beta program, newsletter, or similar program, (4) submit feedback, or other inquiries. 

## How We Use Personally Identifiable Information

Respondus uses your personally identifiable information to bill your credit card for purchases, to confirm your orders, to prevent fraud against you, and to contact you. For example, when you place an order on Respondus.com, we need to know your name, institution, e-mail address, address, and credit card information. This allows us to fulfill your order and notify you of your order status. 

Respondus.com also compiles aggregate data from all of our visitors to prepare internal reports about which pages are popular, how many total unique users visit our site, and different traffic patterns. Respondus does not combine your personally identifiable information with information about pages visited. 

## Who We Disclose Personally Identifiable Information To

Respondus, Inc. will not sell, rent, trade or disclose your personally identifiable information to anyone except as explained in this policy. 

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, marketing our products, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes or share it with an additional party, 

Respondus may also disclose your personal information to law enforcement personnel, government officials, or others when we, in our sole discretion, believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent violations of the law, injury to person or property, or any harm to Respondus.com or others. 

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy companies or assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that Respondus, Inc., or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will likely be one of the transferred assets. 

## Third-Party Service Providers 

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, processing payments, and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

Individual student purchases of Respondus Monitor will redirect the user to PayPal, a secure web site that automatically encrypts confidential information transmitted from the computer to PayPal using the Secure Sockets Layer protocol (SSL) with 128 bit encryption. Credit card or debit information is used only for that particular transaction and is not stored by Respondus. A name and email address is gathered during the purchase but this information will only be used for matters relating to the transaction itself. For information about the privacy policy for PayPal, please click [here](https://cms.paypal.com/cgi-bin/marketingweb?cmd=_render-content&content_ID=ua/Privacy_full&locale.x=en_US). 

## **Software Updates**

The Respondus software will periodically and automatically check for a software update at the Respondus.com web site. No information about your computer hardware and software is collected by Respondus, Inc. during this process. Instead, the Respondus software retrieves information from Respondus.com and will display a message if an update is available.

## **Security**

## How We Protect Your Information

Every time you order a product from Respondus.com, it will be transmitted on a secure server (SSL) that encrypts all of your personal information before it is sent to us. 

No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Although Respondus.com is committed to protecting your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you send to Respondus, and you do so at your own risk. 

## **Cookies and Privacy**

## What A Cookie Is

A "cookie" is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies (and similar tracking technologies such as web beacons) store information about your use of a particular web site or service and are typically used to make services more convenient and personalized. Most cookies are "session cookies," which are automatically deleted whenever you leave a web site (and end the "session"). Some cookies remain on your computer until you remove them. 

## How We Use Cookies

We use cookies on our website (1) to estimate the number of visitors to our web site, (2) to measure general traffic patterns,(3) to store the items you've placed in your shopping cart, and (4) to improve your web browsing experience. Most browsers permit you to set the browser to accept, reject, or notify you of cookie use. However, some parts of the Respondus.com site may not function properly if your browser is set to reject cookies. 

Our shopping cart will remember your cart contents for up to 14 days, for the convenience of our returning customers. It does not retain personal information of any kind, only products added to your shopping cart. 

The Administrator Area of Respondus.com (used only by campus-wide licensees of Respondus applications) also uses session cookies that allows the user to navigate from one page to the next without having to login again for each page.

In addition, some Respondus applications use cookies, as described below:

**Respondus 4.0**  
Respondus 4.0 is an offline authoring tool for creating, managing and publishing online assessments. Respondus 4.0 has an integration with the Respondus Test Bank Network, which contains official publisher test banks formatted for Respondus applications. The Test Bank Network feature within Respondus 4.0 uses a session cookie that allows the user to navigate from one page of the Test Bank Network feature to the next page without having to login on each page.

**StudyMate.com**  
StudyMate.com is a cloud-based hosting service that works in conjunction with StudyMate Author and StudyMate Class. Users can create learning activities from either StudyMate application, and publish them to a StudyMate.com URL. Students can then access the activities from the URL.

StudyMate.com uses a session cookie that allows the user to navigate between items in an activity so that the server can keep track of activities completed, activity scores, etc.

**StudyMate Class**  
StudyMate Class is a web-based application that integrates with the learning management system. StudyMate Class uses a single cookie to remember the last tab accessed by the user. If the user blocks the use of cookies in their browser, StudyMate Class simply won't remember the last tab the user accessed. All other features will work normally.

StudyMate Class also has an integration with the Respondus Test Bank Network, which contains official publisher test banks formatted for Respondus applications. The Test Bank Network feature within StudyMate Class uses a session cookie that allows the user to navigate from one page of the Test Bank Network feature to the next page without having to login on each page. 

## Cookies and Third-Party Service Providers

In addition to using our own cookies, we work with other companies to help provide you with the best experience on our website. Cookies or web beacons may be used to transmit information to the servers of our service providers, such as Google Analytics and AdWords. This allows us to analyze and improve our website and marketing based on anonymous information about browsing activity on the site. These third-party service providers may also retain and use anonymous, aggregated data for their businesses, such as to improve their products and services.

On our website, we may collect information about your online activities for use in offering you tailored advertisements about our products. We may use features of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers. This includes obtaining specific visitor cookie data, such as the source, medium and keywords used to visit our Site. This automated technology helps us track and manage the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.

You may see Respondus ads on other websites based on your visits to our Site because we participate in third-party advertising networks, such as Google Adwords remarketing service. These allow us to target customized messaging based on users' demographic data, browsing history and inferred interests. The networks track your browser across multiple websites, and use this information to show you advertisements that are targeted to suit your interests.

Users may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the Google Advertising Opt-out Page or the Google Analytics Opt-out Page. Users may opt out of third party vendor use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt-out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

## **Children and Privacy**

## Our Policy For Guests Under Age 18

Respondus.com is committed to protecting the privacy of children. We encourage parents and guardians to explore the Internet with their children or students. Visitors under age 18 should not submit any personally identifiable information to Respondus.com.

## **How You Can Change Your Information**

## Updating, Correcting, Or Deleting Your Information

Because your account information is stored offline for added security, there is no provision for you to manually edit your account information via the web browser. 

If you receive an e-mail from us, you can have your e-mail address edited or deleted from a particular list by replying to the e-mail message with the word REMOVE as the subject. 

Please understand that we maintain different mailing lists, such as one for registered users of Respondus LE and another for people who have signed up to participate in a beta program. If you have provided us information at different times or for different purposes, it may be necessary to have your e-mail address removed from multiple lists. 

## **Contact Information**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this web site, you can contact 

> Respondus, Inc.  
>  P.O. Box 3247  
>  Redmond, WA 98073-3247  
>  privacy@respondus.com
